Mateo Gregory

Systems Engineer & Computer Science Full-Stack Engineer Project Manager Mail: magremenez@gmail.com

Linkedin: Marthox Website: Marthox.com Phone: (+57) 316 4193085

System Engineer from Universidad del Valle, proficient in English (B2 certified), with knowledge and experience mainly in Python and JavaScript and some experience in Java, C#, Ruby and Elixir. I have experience in frameworks and libraries such as React, NodeJS, Django, Flask, Fast-Api, Phoenix, Svelte and Rails. Version control (Git) and remote version control hosting platforms (GitHub).

Experience

Software Engineer at SoftServe (February 2024 - Actual)

- Contribute to the deployment and manteinance of integrations made for customers in biology and medicine fields, by developing new features, fixing existing bugs and refactoring legacy code.
- Managing serverless integrations, by developing and deploying new features, fixing existing bugs, and refactoring the codebase, using AWS services like Lambda, API Gateway, S3, DynamoDB, and SQS.
- Identify, triage, and resolve issues in the integrations, by monitoring application logs using tools like Cloud-Watch, Datadog, Sumologic, and Sentry, leading to a 98% uptime of the integrations.
- Finding and deleting unused resources in the cloud, reducing the cost of the infrastructure and improving the performance of the application.
- Writing performance tests for the application, identifying bottlenecks and improving the performance of the application, leading up to 800% performance improvement in certain endpoints.
- Contributing with talks and workshops about software development, cloud services, and best practices in the company, leading to a better understanding of the technologies used in the company and by our clients.
- Contributing to social projects in the company, by teaching and guiding students in the development of software projects, leading to a better understanding of the technologies used in the industry and a better preparation for the students future.
- Leading the Python community in the company, by organizing talks, workshops, and hackathons, leading to a better understanding of the language and the best practices in the company.

Skills and tools: Python, TypeScript, JavaScript, AWS, Serverless, Lambda, API Gateway, S3, DynamoDB, SQS, CloudWatch, Datadog, Sumologic, Sentry, Git, Agile Development, Project Management, Performance Testing.

Full-Stack Engineer at Inchcape (October 2023 - February 2024)

- Contribute to over ten websites in over five countries by mantaining, developing new features, fixing existing bugs and refactoring the codebase, leading to opening new markets expecting to increase the company's revenue.
- Improve the user experience of the websites by developing features specific for each country, and by following user-centered design principles, increasing the user engagement and the conversion rate.

Skills and tools: C# (C-Sharp), JavaScript, Html, Css, .Net, Umbraco, Atlassian, Jira, Git, Agile Software Development, Project Management.

Backend Engineer at Reserve (July 2022 - May 2023)

- Optimize, refactor and create over ten API endpoints, by implementing new features and fixing existing bugs, improving the stability of the application up to 99.98%.
- Open the door to the Mexican market by integrating a third-party remittances provider, allowing users to withdraw and deposit money using cash, reaching to a market of \$58.5 billion.
- Improve the robustness of the application in different workload scenarios, by implementing a customizable load testing tool, allowing the team to identify bottlenecks and improve the performance of the application.

Skills and tools: Python, JavaScript, Html, Css, FastAPI, React, Full-Stack Backend Development, RESTful API Development, API Integrations, Git, Agile Software Development, Project Management.

Full-Stack Engineer at Kommit(October 2021 - July 2022)

- Improve stability and functionality of Podnation by implementing new features and fixing existing bugs, mantaining the already high aplication uptime of 99.99%.
- Release a new feature for Podnation allowing users to create and share clips of their favorite podcasts, increasing the user engagement and the conversion rate by 10%.
- Refactor and enhance a U.S. Military Foundation's hardware device driver, significantly aiding speech-impaired Parkinson's patients, achieving 99.99% improvement in application robustness and stability.

Skills and tools: JavaScript, Elixir, Ruby, React, AdonisJs, ElectronJs, Phoenix, Ruby on Rails, Full-Stack Development, Git, Agile Software Development, Project Management.

Freelance Full-Stack Engineer (January 2021 - August 2021)

- Develop a patient-specific, teeth-like interface, demographically optimized for the target audience, by implementing a custom React component library, increasing user engagement by 15%.
- Craft intuitive user interfaces, optimized for the target audience demographic to enhance user experience and engagement, by implementing a custom React component, increasing user engagement by 15%.
- Built a role-based database model for efficient management of patient, doctor, and appointment data assuring data integrity and security.
- Oversaw deployment, setup, and configuration of the application on Digital Ocean servers using Docker, ensuring a smooth and efficient deployment process.

Skills: JavaScript, Python, SQL, React, Flask, PostgreSQL, Docker, Digital Ocean, Freelance Development, Full-Stack Development, Project Management, Git, Agile Software Development, RESTful API Development.

Soft Skills

Autonomy, Teamwork, Goal-Oriented, Leadership, Conflict Management, Teaching Skills, Active Listening, Clear Communication, Problem-Solving, Flexibility, Creative Thinking, Time Management, Attention to Detail, User-Centric Approach, Analytical Skills, Emotional Intelligence, Project Management, Persistence.

Education

Degree of Systems Engineering at Universidad del valle Master in Systems Engineer at Universidad del valle (June 2016 - December 2021) (January 2023 - Now)

Academic Experience

Complexity and optimization

- SAT Reductor
- Electric Station

Image processing

- Image processing
- MIA

Software development

- UV energy
- Nova

Artificial Intelligence

- Hex Agent
- Sokoban Agents

Networking

GNS3 topology

Virtualization

- Vitual Box Rest API

Extras

- Universidad del valle academic accompaniment monitor
- Universidad del valle custom accompaniment monitor
- Attendant to "Pioneras-Dev" gamification workshop by Edwin Gamboa
- Work on writing an academic paper with Valeria Rivera, Emily Carvajal, and Jose Bernal
- Assistant to the 13th Colombian Congress of computing